This is just an extra tip, this happens to me a lot when I 'm hand sewing, when I'm using regular thread if there's any moisture in the air or, if there's any moisture on your hands, what' going to happen is the thread is going to start to act up and, it's going to tangle itself while you're trying to stitch and, there's nothing more annoying than tangled up thread and trying to un-knot and having to start over because it knotted in the middle.
So, this is a trick that I use, there's such a thing called, tailors wax.
You can get it at any sewing store or, this is wax from a candle.
This works as well too.
What you want to do is just kind of run your thread through that wax, just coat the thread with wax and, that will really prevent your thread from tangling on you.
You can also find it in a lot of sewing stores, packages of thread that are specifically for hand sewing only and, there all waxed and there all a little thicker.
They don't come in a spool; they come like in a tuft.
Almost like if you get fake hair or something.
So, you get a bunch of threads and their all waxed and, you can use those.
But, if you have nothing else and, your threads bunching up and, it's raining outside or, your hands are slightly moist, go ahead and take some wax from a candle, take some wax that's around just drag it through.
You'll have waxed thread and it will just move through your fabric much simpler.